<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Efforts and Courage are not enough without Purpose and Direction - John F. Kennedy</description>
    <link>
    https://cottley.github.io</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Quindecim</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Quindecim. A game idea I have for my Alexa-powered smart speakers. It’s essentially a number matching and memory game with a maximum of fifteen numbers. The aim of the game is to descramble a scrambled list of numbers in as few moves as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/Quindecim</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/Quindecim</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>So many frameworks, oh my!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;With all the Alexa work I have planned, I decided to create a project called Argyle, named from Tobago’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.destinationtnt.com/argyle-waterfall/&quot;&gt;largest waterfall&lt;/a&gt;. I had looked at &lt;a href=&quot;https://laravel.com/&quot;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://phalconphp.com/en/&quot;&gt;Phalcon&lt;/a&gt; but I got the white-screen-of-nothing and no packages to install respectively after trying to install these frameworks. So, I decided to take a step back and worry about the front end and whole framework thing later. Instead I would focus on creating a nice JSON based API that I can use for whatever front end (web, android app, alexa etc.) I decided to use.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/So-many-frameworks-oh-my</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/So-many-frameworks-oh-my</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Oh, Oracle session, let me know</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Oracle. Love it or hate it, it’s all over the place and the basis of many enterprise solutions. While there may be commerical system monitoring and analysis solutions, sometimes (due to cost, speed or simplicity) you just need a quick and dirty solution to make sure you know what’s going on in your database. In this post I am going to discuss how to use a script that I’ve written that lets you monitor the session metric in Oracle’s v$sysmetric view and sends an email if the session metric is over some prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/oh-oracle-session-let-me-know</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/oh-oracle-session-let-me-know</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Sometimes I forget</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about having lots of smart plugs and bulbs connected to Alexa is the convenience of yelling at your devices to turn on and off. While you can schedule devices to turn on and off at specific times, I have to admit that from time to time I get caught up in doing something else and forget the device on. This happens especially with rooms that I don’t frequent every day, like the storage room in the back of the house or where the washer and dryer are. In general I might be in one of those places for maybe 10 minutes so if I forget to turn off the lights (which can happen because there is a door right behind there and I habitually close it) it would be good if something turned the lights off for me, say, after 20 minutes. It might be usefull for the garage as well as after those lights are turned on and we move what we need to from the car into the house, the garage lights might stay on by accident as well.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/sometimes-i-forget</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/sometimes-i-forget</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Can you carry me back?</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There are certain apps I use every day, and, not surprisingly, most of them are from google. While google has its google maps and navigation software, from my experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waze.com/&quot;&gt;Waze&lt;/a&gt; is the better app and service. As much as I like Waze, I have a small peve about how it works, more specifically, how the favorites feature of it works. Waze can figure out where you live and work based on how many times you keep going and returning to those places and it does a pretty good job when you are looking for companies or businesses by name or even addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/can-you-carry-me-back</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/can-you-carry-me-back</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Alexa and Youtube music videos</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One day, maybe, far into the future, tech giants would work together to provide the best set of services for everyone. Or maybe we’ll have to hack together that future ourselves. Between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/2123052/clash-tech-titans-google-bans-youtube-amazon-devices-escalating-dispute&quot;&gt;Google banning Youtube from some Amazon devices&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/2018/03/02/amazon-still-isnt-selling-chromecast-nearly-three-months-initial-announcement/&quot;&gt;Amazon banning Chromecast&lt;/a&gt; from its store-of-everything (which should now be renamed store-of-everything-except-chromecast) there is probably no way anyone is going to provide a nice music service app for Alexa which has a playlist of popular youtube music from trending music videos.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/alexa-youtube-music-videos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/alexa-youtube-music-videos</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Something Something Food</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Food. When you’re hungry, there’s nothing like it, but when you’re not you want to save it for later. Given how many people in the world don’t know where their next meal is coming from, I consider myself immeasurably lucky to state that I’ve never worried about that. Ok, when I get wifey upset about something enough it can get a bit dicey, but generally food is there and not something to be wasted. As a general rule we like to keep food in the fridge or freezer but sometimes (more than I’d like) food gets pushed to the back of the fridge in some forgotten about container and is only discovered after some deep rummaging around. Unfortunately with all the other things people are busy with these days, keeping track of the food in the fridge, when the food was put in, what should be eaten first and how much of it is left is difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/something-something-food</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/something-something-food</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Read my mind Alexa</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve tricked out the house with Alexa compatible gadgets, a bunch of plugs, a whole set of bulbs and three echo dots in three different rooms. I was watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_First_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;The First&lt;/a&gt; and there are lots of sci-fi type things in the show, which is primarily actually a drama with sci-fi things occassionally going wrong. So they have the standard sci-fi-ish stuff with one of the main characters living in a smart house and another one in a smarter house. Typical future expectation like you walk into a room and lights come on and fireplace starts etc. I saw one of the characters ask for the TV to turn on by saying “screen on” or something similar into the ether and the TV screen turned on with the channel showing what he wanted to see. That got me thinking, I’m pretty sure I should be able to do that with Alexa and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/what-is-amazon-alexa-routines/&quot;&gt;Routines&lt;/a&gt; and the only real difference is that I would have to say the wakeword, Alexa, first.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/read-my-mind-alexa</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/read-my-mind-alexa</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Website Redesign</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a number of websites over the years in one form or the other. Usually the websites were project websites that happened to have a small about section where I wrote something short and unmemorable about myself. Unfortunately I got busy and maintaining those websites got de-prioritized, finally existing in some internet archive somewhere and disappearing from active use. The world has changed a bit since then and I got curious as to the advancements of static site generators like &lt;a href=&quot;https://forrest.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Forest&lt;/a&gt;. A static site generator uses dynamic logic to create static websites that load faster and would be easier to maintain for someone working part-time on site maintenace, like me.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 10:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/website-redesign</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/website-redesign</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Moruga for simple python text manipulation</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For Moruga I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/moruga</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/moruga</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Software Download Catalog for a more user friendly download list</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For softwaredownloadcatalog I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Spsimplefileupload for simple sharepoint uploads</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For spsimplefileupload I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 14:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Talparo for WMS tile caching</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For Talparo I am the unofficial MSI packager.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/talparo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/talparo</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>BunnyX Content Modification Proxy Server</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For BunnyX I am the creator, software architect and the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/bunnyx</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/bunnyx</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Firefox MAF</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For MAF I am the creator and initially the sole developer. Now MAF is maintained by Paolo Amadini.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/firefox-maf</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/firefox-maf</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to my little corner</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to my little corner of the Internet. I’m glad you can stop by :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://cottley.github.io/welcome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://cottley.github.io/welcome</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
