<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://cottley.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://cottley.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-02T14:19:25-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/</id><title type="html">Christopher Ottley</title><subtitle>Efforts and Courage are not enough without Purpose and Direction - John F. Kennedy</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Oh, Oracle session, let me know</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/oh-oracle-session-let-me-know" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh, Oracle session, let me know" /><published>2018-10-02T04:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-02T04:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/oh-oracle-session-let-me-know</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/oh-oracle-session-let-me-know">&lt;p&gt;Oracle. Love it or hate it, it’s all over the place and the basis of many enterprise solutions. While there may be commerical system monitoring and analysis solutions, sometimes (due to cost, speed or simplicity) you just need a quick and dirty solution to make sure you know what’s going on in your database. In this post I am going to discuss how to use a script that I’ve written that lets you monitor the session metric in Oracle’s v$sysmetric view and sends an email if the session metric is over some prescribed limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this to work we need a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Root access to the database server to setup the cron job (well we could set it up using another account, like the oracle server account, but who wants to try to find random crontabs all over the place in a few years when we inevitably forget about this?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Local database system access to get access to the v$sysmetric database view&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to the sqlplus command at a bash prompt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mail client &lt;a href=&quot;https://linux.die.net/man/1/mailx&quot;&gt;mailx&lt;/a&gt; installed and accessible at a command prompt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An open SMTP server (ok this is not necessary as mailx supports lots of secure mail services, but I’m assuming you have some internal accessible only SMTP server available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let us download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/cottley/script_stuff/master/check_oracle_session/check_oracle_session.sh&quot;&gt;check_oracle_session.sh script&lt;/a&gt; from my github script_stuff repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my test environment I have a user, oracle with a home folder in /home/oracle/.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we place the downloaded check_oracle_session.sh script in the /home/oracle/ folder and make it executable for the oracle user. We can make it executable (and leave it read-only) for everyone by executing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;chmod 555 check_oracle_session.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all is setup properly you can run the script and see the script options by executing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;./check_oracle_session.sh -h
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the options that the script accepts to execute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
NAME:
  check_oracle_session.sh - Automatic Oracle Database Instance Session Checker v1.0

SYNOPSIS:
  check_oracle_session.sh [options]
  Run automated check for the number of sessions for a oracle database instance.
  The script will execute a notification once the number of sessions exceeds
  a specified limit.

OPTIONS:
  -h, --help
    Show this message
  -l, --limit integerlimit
    Specify the session limit you would like to use so that notifications go
    out when the number of sessions meet or exceed this number. E.g. -l 100
  -s, --smtpserver smtpserver
    Specify the smtp server to use when sending notifications
    E.g. -s mail.mycompany.com
  -f, --from fromemailaddress
    Specify the email address the email will appear to come from when there
    are notifications as a result of the limit being met or exceeded
    E.g. -f noreply@mycompany.com
  -t, --to toemailaddress
    Specify the email address to email when limit has been met or exeeded
    E.g. -t me@mycompany.com
  -v, --verbose
    Verbose output. Note: This will send an email even if the limit has not
    been met or exceeded
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example invocation that is checking if the session limit has met or exceeded 50 sessions, using the SMTP server mail.mycompany.com, with the email coming from noreply@mycompany.com and the email being sent to me@mycompany.com:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
./check_oracle_session.sh -l 50 -s mail.mycompany.com -f noreply@mycompany.com -t me@mycompany.com
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This script assumes that the oracle environment has been setup so that you can use sqlplus at a command prompt and connect as the system DBA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my environment, I also have a seperate oracle.bash file that I source to set the ORACLE_SID, the TNS_ADMIN home etc. You may or may not have a similar configuration, however whatever steps you need to get sqlplus working at a command prompt, that’s what you need to do to test sqlplus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
[oracle@mydatabase ~]$ sqlplus / as sysdba

SQL*Plus: Release 12.1.0.2.0 Production on Tue Oct 2 10:52:36 2018

Copyright (c) 1982, 2014, Oracle.  All rights reserved.


Connected to:
Oracle Database 12c Enterprise Edition Release 12.1.0.2.0 - 64bit Production
With the Partitioning, OLAP, Advanced Analytics and Real Application Testing options

SQL&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can easily test our script to ensure the notifications work by asking it to send an email with a low limit, like 0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
./check_oracle_session.sh -l 0 -s mail.mycompany.com -f noreply@mycompany.com -t me@mycompany.com
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that works, we can now schedule the script to run every 5 minutes via cron.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the crontab we change to the oracle user (su - oracle) and execute the command (-c) in double quotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my test environment I source the oracle.bash to set the environment variables and then run the script with the parameters tested earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
*/5 * * * * su - oracle -c &quot;source /home/oracle/oracle.bash &amp;gt; /dev/null &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /home/oracle/check_oracle_session.sh -l 50 -s mail.mycompany.com -f noreply@mycompany.com -t me@mycompany.com&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your oracle user has the environment variables set already and you don’t need to source any configuration scripts you can use the below crontab entry instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
*/5 * * * * su - oracle -c &quot;/home/oracle/check_oracle_session.sh -l 50 -s mail.mycompany.com -f noreply@mycompany.com -t me@mycompany.com&quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once complete you should get confirmation that the crontab has been saved and installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
[root@mydatabase ~]# crontab -e
no crontab for root - using an empty one
crontab: installing new crontab
[root@mydatabase ~]#
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Voila! The script will run every 5 minutes and notify you via email if the session limit has been exceeded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also track the individual runs of the script by looking at the /var/log/check_oracle_session.log.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
[root@mydatabase ~]# tail -f /var/log/check_oracle_session.log
2018-10-02T12:05:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 48
2018-10-02T12:10:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 50
2018-10-02T12:15:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 50
2018-10-02T12:20:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 49
2018-10-02T12:25:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 48
2018-10-02T12:30:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 48
2018-10-02T12:35:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 48
2018-10-02T12:40:02-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 48
2018-10-02T12:45:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 48
2018-10-02T12:50:01-0500 Limit is: 50 and No. Of Sessions is: 48
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now extend this script if desired and make modifications to monitor multiple metrics, possibly add logic to check the average value of the metric (using v$sysmetric_summary) and only give an alert if the new value for the metric is, say, 10% over the average instead of a hard coded value. You can also add more notification options, such as notifications to a slack channel or even a text message when you are out of wireless (but not cell network) range depending on the API interfaces you have available.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Stuff" /><category term="Howto" /><category term="Scripts" /><category term="Oracle" /><category term="Bash" /><summary type="html">Oracle. Love it or hate it, it’s all over the place and the basis of many enterprise solutions. While there may be commerical system monitoring and analysis solutions, sometimes (due to cost, speed or simplicity) you just need a quick and dirty solution to make sure you know what’s going on in your database. In this post I am going to discuss how to use a script that I’ve written that lets you monitor the session metric in Oracle’s v$sysmetric view and sends an email if the session metric is over some prescribed limit.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alexa and Youtube music videos</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/alexa-youtube-music-videos" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alexa and Youtube music videos" /><published>2018-09-28T04:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-28T04:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/alexa-youtube-music-videos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/alexa-youtube-music-videos">&lt;p&gt;One day, maybe, far into the future, tech giants would work together to provide the best set of services for everyone. Or maybe we’ll have to hack together that future ourselves. Between &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scmp.com/news/world/article/2123052/clash-tech-titans-google-bans-youtube-amazon-devices-escalating-dispute&quot;&gt;Google banning Youtube from some Amazon devices&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidpolice.com/2018/03/02/amazon-still-isnt-selling-chromecast-nearly-three-months-initial-announcement/&quot;&gt;Amazon banning Chromecast&lt;/a&gt; from its store-of-everything (which should now be renamed store-of-everything-except-chromecast) there is probably no way anyone is going to provide a nice music service app for Alexa which has a playlist of popular youtube music from trending music videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m 99% sure this is against Youtube’s terms of service, but it would be an interesting workflow to try to implement. We would need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a list of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/feed/trending&quot;&gt;trending videos&lt;/a&gt; on Youtube parsed into some sort of feed that would give titles and URLs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Filter the videos to search for anything that has the words “Official Video”, “Official Music” or “Music Video” somewhere in the title&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the URLs for that filter and check it against a database of videos already processed so we don’t reprocess any old ones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grab the video (and extract audio?) using something like &lt;a href=&quot;http://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Convert / extract audio to be playable via Alexa via &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.amazon.com/docs/custom-skills/speech-synthesis-markup-language-ssml-reference.html#h3_converting_mp3&quot;&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Store the extracted audio somewhere where we have an Internet facing https server
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do not use S3, don’t want any account bans&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A little linux server (maybe rpi based) that has apache and some storage should do the trick&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;Letsencrypt&lt;/a&gt; certificate with a dynamic dns hostname would be needed as well&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write a script that dynamically selects from the extracted audio files (maybe served from the audio server, maybe not)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Implement a skill with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.amazon.com/docs/custom-skills/audioplayer-interface-reference.html&quot;&gt;audioplayer interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, yell at Alexa to ask youtube to play trending music and we should actually get some music piping back at us. We could even go further and implement some functionality to ask youtube what’s playing and it would recite the title of the video back at us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Half-baked ideas" /><category term="Alexa" /><summary type="html">One day, maybe, far into the future, tech giants would work together to provide the best set of services for everyone. Or maybe we’ll have to hack together that future ourselves. Between Google banning Youtube from some Amazon devices and Amazon banning Chromecast from its store-of-everything (which should now be renamed store-of-everything-except-chromecast) there is probably no way anyone is going to provide a nice music service app for Alexa which has a playlist of popular youtube music from trending music videos.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Something Something Food</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/something-something-food" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Something Something Food" /><published>2018-09-27T05:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-27T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/something-something-food</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/something-something-food">&lt;p&gt;Food. When you’re hungry, there’s nothing like it, but when you’re not you want to save it for later. Given how many people in the world don’t know where their next meal is coming from, I consider myself immeasurably lucky to state that I’ve never worried about that. Ok, when I get wifey upset about something enough it can get a bit dicey, but generally food is there and not something to be wasted. As a general rule we like to keep food in the fridge or freezer but sometimes (more than I’d like) food gets pushed to the back of the fridge in some forgotten about container and is only discovered after some deep rummaging around. Unfortunately with all the other things people are busy with these days, keeping track of the food in the fridge, when the food was put in, what should be eaten first and how much of it is left is difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how about an Alexa skill which reduces/eliminates food wastage. Essentially an online, voice interface to inventory management for food in the fridge. We could even extend it to the freezer, add multiple fridges/freezers and even set re-order levels for certain items. We could know what’s in the fridge without having to open the door, saving electricity as the temperature would not raise with the door being kept open while we rummage around, unsure as to what we want to get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Half-baked ideas" /><category term="Alexa" /><summary type="html">Food. When you’re hungry, there’s nothing like it, but when you’re not you want to save it for later. Given how many people in the world don’t know where their next meal is coming from, I consider myself immeasurably lucky to state that I’ve never worried about that. Ok, when I get wifey upset about something enough it can get a bit dicey, but generally food is there and not something to be wasted. As a general rule we like to keep food in the fridge or freezer but sometimes (more than I’d like) food gets pushed to the back of the fridge in some forgotten about container and is only discovered after some deep rummaging around. Unfortunately with all the other things people are busy with these days, keeping track of the food in the fridge, when the food was put in, what should be eaten first and how much of it is left is difficult.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Read my mind Alexa</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/read-my-mind-alexa" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Read my mind Alexa" /><published>2018-09-27T04:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-27T04:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/read-my-mind-alexa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/read-my-mind-alexa">&lt;p&gt;I’ve tricked out the house with Alexa compatible gadgets, a bunch of plugs, a whole set of bulbs and three echo dots in three different rooms. I was watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_First_(TV_series)&quot;&gt;The First&lt;/a&gt; and there are lots of sci-fi type things in the show, which is primarily actually a drama with sci-fi things occassionally going wrong. So they have the standard sci-fi-ish stuff with one of the main characters living in a smart house and another one in a smarter house. Typical future expectation like you walk into a room and lights come on and fireplace starts etc. I saw one of the characters ask for the TV to turn on by saying “screen on” or something similar into the ether and the TV screen turned on with the channel showing what he wanted to see. That got me thinking, I’m pretty sure I should be able to do that with Alexa and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitaltrends.com/home/what-is-amazon-alexa-routines/&quot;&gt;Routines&lt;/a&gt; and the only real difference is that I would have to say the wakeword, Alexa, first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I tried it and it works well enough as I have the TV plugged into a smart plug and the TV is an older LED one that returns to its on/off state whenever power is turned off and back on. As long as I don’t use the remote to turn off the TV, it works. Here is where it starts to get complicated, I have, &lt;em&gt;gasp&lt;/em&gt; two TVs. There’s one in the living room and one in the bedroom (which also is on a smart plug and has an echo dot nearby). If I want my new fancy routine to work with the TV in the living toom and the TV in the bedroom I’d need to say &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; screen. I’d need to say “living screen on” or “bedroom screen on” and while that would work, it’s not as nice as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to say “screen on” near the echo dot in the living room and it turns on the living room TV and say “screen on” near the echo dot in the bedroom and it turns on the bedroom TV. The problem with this is that Alexa doesn’t care where it hears the command, it executes without additional context. Now that I’ve discussed the problem, here’s my idea for a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that the Alexa API now lets you request additional location information for your skill, inclusive of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.amazon.com/docs/custom-skills/device-address-api.html#get-the-api-access-token-and-device-id&quot;&gt;Device ID&lt;/a&gt;. To get the routine to work though, I would need to create a proxy &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.amazon.com/docs/smarthome/understand-the-smart-home-skill-api.html&quot;&gt;smart home skill&lt;/a&gt; that would hopefully have the device id in the request JSON somewhere. Once I can get that, I’d need to find the devices associated with the device id, which I would have to setup externally and then change the devices to suit. Seeing as there is no API for me to automate Alexa itself (why Amazon, whyyyyy?), it looks like I’ll have to figure out the API to control the devices outside of the Alexa ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out I was a bit lucky and bought a set of TP Link based bulbs and plugs and it turns out that someone already has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/konsumer/tplink-lightbulb&quot;&gt;command line app&lt;/a&gt; (nodejs based) that I should be able to use to turn my bulbs and plugs on and off. It looks like I should only need to learn one API and command line the rest of it based on the plug and bulb ids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it a bit more, I shouldn’t even have to say “Alexa, screen on”, I should just have to say “Alexa, screen” and the skill will know the state of the plug. If it’s on it turns it off and if it’s off it turns it on. This should be able to extend to lights as well, “Alexa, lights” should be able to toggle the lights near the device on and off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s see if I can get any traction on this when I get my time machine working. :).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Half-baked ideas" /><category term="Alexa" /><summary type="html">I’ve tricked out the house with Alexa compatible gadgets, a bunch of plugs, a whole set of bulbs and three echo dots in three different rooms. I was watching The First and there are lots of sci-fi type things in the show, which is primarily actually a drama with sci-fi things occassionally going wrong. So they have the standard sci-fi-ish stuff with one of the main characters living in a smart house and another one in a smarter house. Typical future expectation like you walk into a room and lights come on and fireplace starts etc. I saw one of the characters ask for the TV to turn on by saying “screen on” or something similar into the ether and the TV screen turned on with the channel showing what he wanted to see. That got me thinking, I’m pretty sure I should be able to do that with Alexa and Routines and the only real difference is that I would have to say the wakeword, Alexa, first.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website Redesign</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/website-redesign" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website Redesign" /><published>2018-09-26T10:15:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-26T10:15:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/website-redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/website-redesign">&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a number of websites over the years in one form or the other. Usually the websites were project websites that happened to have a small about section where I wrote something short and unmemorable about myself. Unfortunately I got busy and maintaining those websites got de-prioritized, finally existing in some internet archive somewhere and disappearing from active use. The world has changed a bit since then and I got curious as to the advancements of static site generators like &lt;a href=&quot;https://forrest.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Forest&lt;/a&gt;. A static site generator uses dynamic logic to create static websites that load faster and would be easier to maintain for someone working part-time on site maintenace, like me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I generally like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt; products, &lt;a href=&quot;https://forrest.apache.org/&quot;&gt;Apache Forest&lt;/a&gt; doesn’t seem to have been updated for a while and I aimed to find the most popular static site generator in use. In open source, high usage usually means that it’s reasonably maintained and fits some minimal use cases very well. After some research I happened upon &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know Ruby, but the installation seemed pretty straight forward and seeing as GitHub seems to use it for their GitHub pages service, I figured I couldn’t go too wrong. One of the nice things about &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is that there are lots of tutorials and instructions all over the Internet on how to make all sorts of websites with it. GitHub has some good instructions as well, but I decided to see if I could find some instructions that were more generic which would allow me to move my site to anywhere without worrying about any kind of GitHub specific pages config (not that I really saw any, but you never know).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing as a I like to keep things seperated, I fired up a brand spanking new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; 18.04 Desktop VM, did a minimal install, updated everything, installed ssh and I was ready to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a bash prompt, a quick…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install ruby ruby-dev build-essential
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and I was ready to install Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the instructions from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/installation/ubuntu/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and executing at a bash prompt again…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo '# Install Ruby Gems to ~/gems' &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc
echo 'export GEM_HOME=$HOME/gems' &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc
echo 'export PATH=$HOME/gems/bin:$PATH' &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.bashrc
source ~/.bashrc
gem install jekyll bundler
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and now Jekyll is installed. It really was painless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to serve up a site for development…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;jekyll new cottley-site
cd cottley-site/
bundle exec jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…And here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/website-redesign-figure1.png&quot; alt=&quot;website-redesign-figure1&quot; title=&quot;First run with default website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ugh! I mean &lt;em&gt;yay&lt;/em&gt; (obviously), but also, Ugh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, this was about 5 minutes of work (including network downloads), but goshdarnit, first impressions matter. I understand the bare minimalism so you can customize what you want, but, ugh. This was supposed to make my website life easier, not look so, plain. I know I know, there are links to some themes at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Themes.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllthemes.io/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Themes.io&lt;/a&gt; are on the website under the resources, but if you at least give me a link to one of them on the very first site I throw up I’ll be more likely to think that even the minimal effort was worth it because changing the theme is easy and possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a super nice theme called &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllthemes.org/themes/jasper2/&quot;&gt;Jasper2&lt;/a&gt; and spent a few minutes trying to figure out how to get it installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…And you don’t install it, the theme &lt;em&gt;IS&lt;/em&gt; the site and you need to config the site and put the posts in it. Ok, fine. Let’s do a serve in an extracted Jasper2 folder… and it doesn’t work. Of course. At least it tells me I have to install some gems and to run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All seems to be working well until it can’t install nokogiri, whatever that is and suggests that I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install nokogiri -v '1.8.4' --source
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which doesn’t work and so I try&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gem install nokogiri -v '1.8.4' --source 'https://rubygems.org/'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;which still doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the error, it can’t find zlib for some reason so I go looking to install some ruby zlib library. I find one and…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install ruby-zip
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still doesn’t work. Installing a theme shouldn’t be this hard man! Looking at the error further it seems that Jekyll / Ruby invokes gcc to compile some code and it can’t find the zlib header library. I do a&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install libz-dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and manage to install nokogiri ok now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bundle install
bundle exec jekyll serve
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the terminal and I finally, FINALLY have the theme site up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/website-redesign-figure2.png&quot; alt=&quot;website-redesign-figure2&quot; title=&quot;First run with Jasper2 theme&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I play with some config settings, replace some images, start putting in posts and boom, new website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing Jasper2 doesn’t seem to do is generate a nice xml sitemap for me, so I grabbed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-sitemap&quot;&gt;Jekyll Sitemap Generator Plugin&lt;/a&gt; and installed it (which is much easier than the theme crazy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it, I’m going to try continue consolidating my tech rantings here so if at least, dear reader, you don’t find me entertaining, you at least find me informative.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Stuff" /><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">I’ve had a number of websites over the years in one form or the other. Usually the websites were project websites that happened to have a small about section where I wrote something short and unmemorable about myself. Unfortunately I got busy and maintaining those websites got de-prioritized, finally existing in some internet archive somewhere and disappearing from active use. The world has changed a bit since then and I got curious as to the advancements of static site generators like Apache Forest. A static site generator uses dynamic logic to create static websites that load faster and would be easier to maintain for someone working part-time on site maintenace, like me.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Moruga for simple python text manipulation</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/moruga" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moruga for simple python text manipulation" /><published>2018-09-25T14:45:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T14:45:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/moruga</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/moruga">&lt;p&gt;For Moruga I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most software that provides some sort of input or output process can generate ASCII text files. Sometimes the text files are in a format that is unusable by another application that can use the output as input. Occasionally I encounter this situation and so I created a small framework that will let me convert text files using a specified algorithm via a command line. I named the framework Moruga. It is easy to extend by implementing custom Python functions and then calling the script via a command line switch. You can have a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/moruga&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; and start saving time when converting text file formats in Python.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="moruga" /><summary type="html">For Moruga I am the sole developer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Software Download Catalog for a more user friendly download list</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Software Download Catalog for a more user friendly download list" /><published>2018-09-25T14:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T14:30:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog">&lt;p&gt;For softwaredownloadcatalog I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my day to day work I use quite a bit of software. The software is delivered in many different forms, from MSI installers, to executables to ISOs. After some time I realised that I had software stewn all over my computer that was not the easiest thing to keep track of. When I realised this I was also experimenting with a javascript UI library called &lt;a href=&quot;http://w2ui.com/web/&quot;&gt;W2UI&lt;/a&gt;. A few keystrokes later and I created a software download catalog that uses a JSON file for the entries displayed with links to download the software (well, less of a link and more of a double click on a grid entry record). Using W2UI I was able to create an easily searchable, sortable and somewhat attractive user interface for the software archive I was maintaining. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/sdcmirror&quot;&gt;download a copy&lt;/a&gt; for your own private (or Intranet) use at or have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cottley.github.io/sdcmirror/&quot;&gt;a live demo&lt;/a&gt; (fyi - none of the software download links work in the demo).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="softwaredownloadcatalog" /><summary type="html">For softwaredownloadcatalog I am the sole developer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spsimplefileupload for simple sharepoint uploads</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spsimplefileupload for simple sharepoint uploads" /><published>2018-09-25T14:15:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T14:15:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload">&lt;p&gt;For spsimplefileupload I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I needed to generate an Excel report out of another system and make it available to certain people. Automating the creation of the report was a bit of a challenge, but once I got that done, I also had to decide how I could share the report. As the company had a Sharepoint 2010 setup, I figured it would be good to point the users to a specific URL and they could see what they wanted to in Sharepoint. This is where the unimaginatively named spsimplefileupload utility came in. Most of the tools I found online were complicated to setup or were overkill for what I needed to do. As I managed to write the automation I needed via a batch file (yeah, I know) I decided a simple command line utility was all I needed, so that’s what I did. I’ve tested it with Sharepoint 2010 and it works pretty well. There is not much error checking, but usually it just works. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;see the command line options&lt;/a&gt;, download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload&quot;&gt;source code and project&lt;/a&gt; from github or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload/releases/download/0.1.2.0/spsfileupload.exe&quot;&gt;the utility itself&lt;/a&gt; from github’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload/releases&quot;&gt;release page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Spsimplefileupload" /><summary type="html">For spsimplefileupload I am the sole developer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Talparo for WMS tile caching</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/talparo" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Talparo for WMS tile caching" /><published>2018-09-25T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T14:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/talparo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/talparo">&lt;p&gt;For Talparo I am the unofficial MSI packager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mapproxy.org/&quot;&gt;MapProxy&lt;/a&gt; is an open source geospatial data proxy. While it works on Windows and Linux, setting it up as a service on Windows takes some doing. Installing MapProxy on a Linux machine is relatively easy (with the repository setups and such), but after following the Windows installation steps, I was left scratching my head as to why certain things were not working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://talparo.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;Talparo MapProxy&lt;/a&gt; is an unofficial distribution of of MapProxy that lets you easily setup a local MapProxy installation. It solves some of the setup problems I encountered when trying to setup MapProxy for Windows by including Portable Python (so Python installations do not conflict on the machine) and registering the MapProxy as a Windows service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also included a number of configurations for popular tile based map servers so anyone can use them as a WMS source for GIS based visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project had minimal programming involved however there was quite a bit of figuring out how to integrate pieces of MapProxy and its dependencies together. While this may not be so difficult, the real challenge was designing the final product so the end user has the smoothest, easiest time with installing the application. I also wanted to make it an MSI because I prefer a setup database (like a MSI) over an executable installer that is doing who knows what to your machine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="Talparo" /><summary type="html">For Talparo I am the unofficial MSI packager.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BunnyX Content Modification Proxy Server</title><link href="http://cottley.github.io/bunnyx" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BunnyX Content Modification Proxy Server" /><published>2018-09-25T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T14:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://cottley.github.io/bunnyx</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/bunnyx">&lt;p&gt;For BunnyX I am the creator, software architect and the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bunnyx.sourceforge.net/get.php?page=home&quot;&gt;BunnyX&lt;/a&gt; is designed to facilitate web app integration from legacy web apps to provide a more modern API without code changes. &lt;a href=&quot;http://bunnyx.sourceforge.net/get.php?page=home&quot;&gt;BunnyX&lt;/a&gt; started out as an experiment. I’ve always been fascinated by content modification proxies (yes, yes, I know). While many of these proxies provided services such as ad blocking or image conversion, I thought it would be interesting to create a proxy that dynamically changed the format of the main content the user was requesting. The feasibility and usefulness of this became the genus of my Master’s project - &lt;a href=&quot;http://uwispace.sta.uwi.edu/dspace/handle/2139/3443&quot;&gt;“Dynamic Conversion of Legacy Web-based Data for Real Time XML-based Programming”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, the Web was pretty mainstream and everyone was wondering what was next. Supposedly the answer had something to do with XML, a cousin to HTML. Not to much earlier we had gone through the whole Y2K legacy apps scare and it got me thinking about all these web applications that eventually no-one would maintain, but still use because they work. What if you wanted to integrate, extend or change something, but you didn’t have access to the code, how would you do it? It sounded like a content modification proxy was just the thing. I tested BunnyX on various websites, incorporating a number of different libraries and tests to determine extent of load, response time and general usefulness. One of my first applications converted the websites of the local newspapers to an XML based mish-mash of news from all of them at the same time. Unfortunately I never released that app after I showed a number of people and they told me at the time I would have been violating each site’s copyright by releasing the tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BunnyX was so named because the only content modification proxy I found online which seemed halfway decent was named &lt;a href=&quot;http://rabbit-proxy.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;RabbIT&lt;/a&gt; and so I named my project BunnyX as a sort of homage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was still using the Internet via dial up in 2003 and 2004 and my ISP at the time (TSTT) decided that giving people packages based on time and then overcharging them when they went over was the best business plan they could come up with (ah monopolies). I used my fancy smancy BunnyX proxy to scrape the web app they threw up that told you how much time you had spent and how much you had left. This web app by the way didn’t count for you, so you needed to refresh the page to make sure you didn’t go over your limit. I parsed the time and created a little counter with some statistics on how much I used for the day, the average I could use, how many hours (and minutes) I had left and I always stayed under my limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime later I encountered a horribly ancient web application at my workplace (ASP code craziness) which I had to use, but whose interface was stuck in the 1990’s. I thought it would be great to have a mobile interface for the web app so I could check and update data on my phone. Unfortunately the guys maintaining the web app didn’t really have time for converting the app to be mobile friendly so I wondered what I could do to make my life easier. I recalled my BunnyX project (to which I have lost all access to update because I lost access to the recovery email address) and fired it up. It crashed spectacularly, but I designed the code in a fairly modular fashion and with some work and replacing components I had written myself some time ago with open source ones people had developed (I remember when non-blocking IO servers where just getting talked about) I managed to get BunnyX up and running again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key things about BunnyX is that it adds the ability to generate JSON files from your content and using this new functionality I created a mobile website that requested the data through the proxy and displayed the JSON result to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the app to work, I needed a way to request the URL I needed through a proxy without having to connect to the proxy directly. The solution to this was a small PHP proxy I named &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/jsonpcurlproxy&quot;&gt;jsonpcurlproxy&lt;/a&gt; which does exactly as it’s named. It allows cross domain JSON requests (JSONP) and grabs the result via CURL configuring the &lt;a href=&quot;http://curl.haxx.se/&quot;&gt;CURL&lt;/a&gt; request to go through the BunnyX proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mobile based website I created (using &lt;a href=&quot;https://angularjs.org/&quot;&gt;AngularJS&lt;/a&gt; to get it going quickly) worked well, but alas I think my content modification proxy is cursed as, when I asked for feedback from the users in the company, they were enthusiastic until I was quite nicely asked by my headquarters’ management to shut the server down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content modification proxies are fantastic tools if you know how you can fit them into your architecture to solve problems you are encountering. BunnyX and BunnyXPlus are good tools to create content based apps based on HTML based data sources you don’t have access to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christopher Ottley</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="BunnyX" /><summary type="html">For BunnyX I am the creator, software architect and the sole developer.</summary></entry></feed>