<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="https://cottley.github.io/tag/spsimplefileupload/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="https://cottley.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2018-10-05T15:14:28-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://cottley.github.io/tag/spsimplefileupload/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Christopher Ottley | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Efforts and Courage are not enough without Purpose and Direction - John F. Kennedy</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Spsimplefileupload for simple sharepoint uploads</title>
      <link href="https://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spsimplefileupload for simple sharepoint uploads" />
      <published>2018-09-25T14:15:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2018-09-25T14:15:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>https://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="https://cottley.github.io/spsimplefileupload">&lt;p&gt;For spsimplefileupload I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I needed to generate an Excel report out of another system and make it available to certain people. Automating the creation of the report was a bit of a challenge, but once I got that done, I also had to decide how I could share the report. As the company had a Sharepoint 2010 setup, I figured it would be good to point the users to a specific URL and they could see what they wanted to in Sharepoint. This is where the unimaginatively named spsimplefileupload utility came in. Most of the tools I found online were complicated to setup or were overkill for what I needed to do. As I managed to write the automation I needed via a batch file (yeah, I know) I decided a simple command line utility was all I needed, so that’s what I did. I’ve tested it with Sharepoint 2010 and it works pretty well. There is not much error checking, but usually it just works. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;see the command line options&lt;/a&gt;, download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload&quot;&gt;source code and project&lt;/a&gt; from github or &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload/releases/download/0.1.2.0/spsfileupload.exe&quot;&gt;the utility itself&lt;/a&gt; from github’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/spsimplefileupload/releases&quot;&gt;release page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Christopher Ottley</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Projects" />
      
        <category term="Spsimplefileupload" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">For spsimplefileupload I am the sole developer.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
