<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://cottley.github.io/tag/softwaredownloadcatalog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://cottley.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2018-09-28T15:05:41-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://cottley.github.io/tag/softwaredownloadcatalog/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Christopher Ottley | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Efforts and Courage are not enough without Purpose and Direction - John F. Kennedy</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Software Download Catalog for a more user friendly download list</title>
      <link href="http://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Software Download Catalog for a more user friendly download list" />
      <published>2018-09-25T14:30:00-04:00</published>
      <updated>2018-09-25T14:30:00-04:00</updated>
      <id>http://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://cottley.github.io/softwaredownloadcatalog">&lt;p&gt;For softwaredownloadcatalog I am the sole developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my day to day work I use quite a bit of software. The software is delivered in many different forms, from MSI installers, to executables to ISOs. After some time I realised that I had software stewn all over my computer that was not the easiest thing to keep track of. When I realised this I was also experimenting with a javascript UI library called &lt;a href=&quot;http://w2ui.com/web/&quot;&gt;W2UI&lt;/a&gt;. A few keystrokes later and I created a software download catalog that uses a JSON file for the entries displayed with links to download the software (well, less of a link and more of a double click on a grid entry record). Using W2UI I was able to create an easily searchable, sortable and somewhat attractive user interface for the software archive I was maintaining. You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/cottley/sdcmirror&quot;&gt;download a copy&lt;/a&gt; for your own private (or Intranet) use at or have a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cottley.github.io/sdcmirror/&quot;&gt;a live demo&lt;/a&gt; (fyi - none of the software download links work in the demo).&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Christopher Ottley</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Projects" />
      
        <category term="softwaredownloadcatalog" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">For softwaredownloadcatalog I am the sole developer.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
